Matt Coddington | Senior UX/UI Designer

📞 803.873.6587 💟 mattcoddington@gmail.com 🔮 http://mattcoddington

I've been designing for the web for 16 years now, with over 13 of those being in UX/UI design. I've done everything from simple website design to UX/UI for large scale enterprise apps.

Work Experience

Rygen / Dec 2020 - Sep 2022

Senior User Experience Designer

- Sole designer for Corsair, a greenfield Transportation Management System
- Created design system, style guide, and logos for Corsair and several internal apps using Figma

doxy.me / Jun 2020 - Dec 2020

Senior UX/UI Designer

- Helped scale doxy.me's user experience amid growth due to the COVID pandemic
- Conducted user interviews, primarily solo practicing therapists
- Designed analytics dashboard to help users understand the value doxy.me adds to their practice

CoLinx / Oct 2019 - Apr 2020

Programmer / Analyst III

- Worked on features with roughly 75% going to development and 25% to design
- Designed new features/interactions in Sketch / Zeplin and implement them in React / Redux

Benefitfocus / Oct 2018 - Oct 2018

Software Engineer III

 Full time front-end developer working on standalone React projects as well as supporting legacy JS applications; technology used: React, GraphQL, x-state, Backbone, and Dust

CoLinx / Aug 2017 - Oct 2018

Contract UX/UI Designer

- Lead UX/UI designer redesigning the CoLinx eCommerce application
- Created componentized design system using Sketch and Zeplin

Benefitfocus / Nov 2011 - Jan 2017

Senior Visual Interaction Designer

- Lead designer for several large products and features including: Benefitfocus Mobile App, Enrollment (HR Admin Role), Benefitfocus CMS, and the "Manual of Style" design system
- Conducted usability testing including card sorting, user interviews, and moderated usability tests
- Evangelized good UX practices through internal meetings, lunch & learns, and user conferences

Super Duper Publications / Nov 2010 - Aug 2011

Web Designer

- Lead interaction designer and graphic designer on a large SaaS project
- Worked on day-to-day design work for eCommerce portal

Benefitfocus / Aug 2007 - Oct 2010

Web Designer

- Designed and develop several client-facing websites; provided visual design for the UX team
- Worked primarily in Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator) to create various deliverables including websites, presentations, and print work

Professional Skills

- HTML/CSS/JS/ReactJS Proficient in frontend development and have built several SPA's with
 React
- Sketching & wireframing White boarding, Balsamiq mockups, Axure RP wireframing/prototyping
- High fidelity design Polished visual design in Sketch, Figma, Penpot, Photoshop, and Adobe XD
- Interactive prototyping Advanced prototyping in Axure, Invision, UXPin, or HTML/CSS
- User research Card sorting, user interviews, preference testing, and moderated usability testing

Education

University of South Carolina / 2003-2007 **History**

References available upon request